SIMRAN KAUR GREWAL

https://simrankaur5.github.io

PROFILE

I have an interest in user interface particularly the process behind it which enhances user experience and is fundamental since with the click of a button the user can be influenced by the product. This intrigues me because it seems like a simple process but requires creativity and developing an experience to capture a user's attention within seconds.

EDUCATION AND AWARDS

First Class Honours: BSc Computer Science at Goldsmiths, University of London: September 2016 – June 2020 Final year project (Grade: 81%):

Designed CityGo, a web application that creates a walking tour map for its users based on their preferences determined by extensive research and surveys backed by user testing and evaluation. Featured in the Computing Department blogs and websites as one of the best projects.

Relevant Modules:

Interaction Design: Conducted research and created prototypes to evaluate and improve designs in current services/ products.

Web Development: Created websites using HTML, CSS and MYSQL.

Software projects: Group work - created a fitness app using Adobe XD, XCode and Swift. Individual work - created a drawing app and a game using p5.js.

Virgo Fidelis Convent Senior School and Sixth Form: January 2012 – June 2016:

3 A Levels: Mathematics, Chemistry and Biology

12 GCSEs with grades A – C including Mathematics and English.

Received a PIXL Achievement Award for examination success in my GCSE's.

SKILLS

Research and Planning: Identifying Problems, Gathering Information including academic research, user interviews and heuristic evaluation, Usability Testing, Developing Evaluations and Calculating Results

Tools: Adobe XD, Jupyter Notebook, Eclipse, Atom, Visual Studio Code and Node.js

Programming Languages: Python, Java, Angular, HTML, CSS **Database Management:** MySQL, MongoDB, and Firebase **Natural Language Processing:** Keras/TensorFlow

Microsoft Office: Excel, PowerPoint, Word

Language Skills: I can fluently speak English, Punjabi, Swahili and Hindi

WORK EXPERIENCE AND VOLUNTEERING

ICTS Security Agent at Gatwick Airport: July 2018 - March 2019

I was given the responsibility within a team for the security of flights and passengers. Searching passengers and their bags for prohibited items improved my customer service skills. I operated the detective machine that was used to test the swabs used on electronic devices and passengers.

Sales Assistant for WHSmith at Gatwick Airport: January 2017 - December 2017

I managed the store independently; this improved my leadership skills. I gained customer service skills when serving customers at the till. I was responsible for keeping the store clean and re-stocking shelves throughout my shift.

Trainee Pharmacist assistant at Battersea Pharmacy: September 2015

I gained effective and attentive listening and speaking skills while interacting with customers. I performed tasks expected of a pharmacy assistant in sales of OTC and pharmacy medicines.

Trainee Receptionist at Gilroy Court Hotel: June 2013

I was responsible for answering phone calls and replying to e-mails from the local council; this improved my communication skills. We worked as a team to solve problems that guests had during their stay.

I have gained good organisational skills by volunteering at the Gurdwara (Sikh place of worship) every weekend. I am an active member of the Sikh Youth Croydon.

I volunteer for Nishkam SWAT, a non-profit organisation that feeds the homeless. This has increased my resilience and ability to mix with people from different backgrounds.

INTERESTS

My personal lockdown project was to improve my wellbeing and researching skin care products and ingredients that are mis-sold to customers because customers do not usually understand what is suitable for their skin type.

I have always been interested in cooking and I took over meal planning, shopping, and cooking during lockdown for my family. I developed my skills by trying out new recipes.